<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nick Pondel</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nick Pondel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2029 13:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>What dis? A simple little site for sharing things I find interesting.
How?  Build on the blogdown package for R, thanks to the awesome work of Yihui Xie. Continuous Depoyment via Netlify  You can also find me on  Github  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2029 13:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>Contact  nick@nickpondel.com https://github.com/npondel  Education  MPH - Biomedical Informatics  The Ohio State University - 2019 Project: Creating Structured Data from Mixed Free-Text and Categorical Data  Github Repo - PDF Link   Contributed to research on identifying child maltreatement risk factors from EMS record data at Nationwide Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital in Columbus, OH. Publications for this are still pending.   BS - Health and Rehabiliation Sciences  The Ohio State University - 2016 Specialization: Medical Laboratory Science    Credentials  Medical Laboratory Scientist (ASCP) Epic Client Systems Administrator Citrix Virtual Apps and Desktops - Associate  Skills  Coding/Scripting Languages  Extensive experience with R and Shiny AutoHotKey, PowerShell, SQL, and Python   Computer Systems Administration  EHR System Architecture Windows Server and Ubuntu Server   Medical Laboratory  Hematology and Coagulation Laboratory Systems and Automation    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you, TidyR</title>
      <link>/2020/08/21/thank-you-tidyr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/08/21/thank-you-tidyr/</guid>
      <description>While I was working on my MPH program, I had to solve a problem which at the time seemed like a complex task. Combining and transforming some “messy” data with multiple rows per encounter into a tidy dataset for NLP analysis.
messy.data ## id text ## 1 1 hi ## 2 1 some data ## 3 2 woo hoo ## 4 2 more character strings ## 5 3 help me ## 6 4 tidyr as.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post!</title>
      <link>/2020/08/02/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/08/02/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Trying yet again to create a simple website for myself, this time using my old friend R and the blogdown package.
Stick around&amp;hellip;more to come in the future&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>