<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nick Pondel</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nick Pondel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2029 13:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>What dis? A simple little site for sharing things I find interesting.
How?  Build on the blogdown package for R, thanks to the awesome work of Yihui Xie. Continuous Depoyment via Netlify  You can also find me on  Github  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2029 13:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>Links  nick@nickpondel.com https://github.com/npondel  Education  MPH - Biomedical Informatics  The Ohio State University - 2019 Project: Creating Structured Data from Mixed Free-Text and Categorical Data  Github Repo - PDF Link   Contributed to research on identifying child maltreatement risk factors from EMS record data at Nationwide Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital in Columbus, OH. Publications still pending.   BS - Health and Rehabiliation Sciences  The Ohio State University - 2016 Specialization: Medical Laboratory Science    Work  Epic Technical Services (Sept 2019 - Present)  Epic Systems Corporation Client Systems - Hyperspace and Desktop   Medical Laboratory Scientist (May 2016 - Aug 2019)  The Ohio State University Wexner Medical Center Primarily worked in Hematology, Coagulation Studies, and Laboratory Automation    Credentials  Medical Laboratory Scientist (ASCP) Epic Client Systems Administrator Citrix Virtual Apps and Desktops - Associate  Skills  Coding/Scripting Languages  Extensive experience with R and Shiny SQL, AutoHotKey, PowerShell, and Python   Computer Systems Administration  EHR System Architecture Windows and Linux Servers Networking   Medical Laboratory  Hematology and Coagulation Laboratory Systems and Automation    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Chili Recipe</title>
      <link>/2021/02/14/my-chili-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/02/14/my-chili-recipe/</guid>
      <description>Everyone needs a good chili recipe. My fiance hates beans, so Texas chili it is! This is heavily inspired by this recipe.
Ingredients  2 sweet onions, diced 5 garlic cloves, minced 3 serrano peppers 2lbs ground chuck 1tbsp salt 3tbsp ancho chile powder 2tbsp cumin 1tbsp smoked paprika 2 x 14.5oz cans diced tomatoes 1 x 6oz can tomato paste 1 bottle of lager beer 3tbsp masa (regular flour works in a pinch) Olive oil (or canola, or whatever oil) Shredded cheddar Crackers Whatever else you put on chili  Prep  Start some olive oil in a stew pot on medium-high heat Mince the onions and garlic Take the serrano peppers and poke many holes in them  Add solids  Add onions and cook until translucent Add garlic and cook for 1-2mins Add beef and stir until beef is throughly cooked Add spices (salt, chili powder, cumin, paprika) and cook for 5mins  Add liquids  Add tomato paste, diced tomatoes, and toss in the serrano peppers Add 1 cup water and bottle of lager beer Cook on low (just barely bubbling) for 30 mins  Keep simmering  Add another 1 cup water and stir Cook for another 30mins  Thicken it up  Fish out the serrano peppers with tongs Add 3tbps masa and stir Cook for 10 more mins and it&amp;rsquo;s ready to serve  Serve  Serve with your choice of shredded cheddar, oyster crackers, sour cream, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BitBar - Add scripts to your MacOS menu bar</title>
      <link>/2020/09/15/bitbar-add-scripts-to-your-macos-menu-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/15/bitbar-add-scripts-to-your-macos-menu-bar/</guid>
      <description>Via the Automators Podcast I learned about a little utility which one can use to take any script written in shell, Ruby, Python, etc. and output the results as a Mac menu bar item.
The tool is called Bitbar, and it can be downloaded quickly in Homebrew with
~$ brew cask install bitbar
But why&amp;hellip;? With the power of scripting, you can put literally anything into your menu bar, assuming you can write a script to grab that data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you, TidyR</title>
      <link>/2020/08/21/thank-you-tidyr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/08/21/thank-you-tidyr/</guid>
      <description>While I was working on my MPH program, I had to solve a problem which at the time seemed like a complex task. Combining and transforming some “messy” data with multiple rows per encounter into a tidy dataset for NLP analysis.
messy.data ## id text ## 1 1 hi ## 2 1 some data ## 3 2 woo hoo ## 4 2 more character strings ## 5 3 help me ## 6 4 tidyr as.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post!</title>
      <link>/2020/08/02/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/08/02/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Trying yet again to create a simple website for myself, this time using my old friend R and the blogdown package.
Stick around&amp;hellip;more to come in the future&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>